A Guide to the René Jules Dubos papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA122
Rockefeller Archive Center
- (VIDEO CASSETTES), moving image
  - "L'Optimiste Malgre Tout, Part I: De La Terre et des Hommes", narrator and interviewer, Jean-Paul Escande [in French, with French and English transcriptions, folder 1]. Channel 2, Paris, France, filmed in 1980 - poor sound quality [U-Matic, transformed from French system; 55 minutes], moving image (Box 110, Tape 11)
  - "L'Optimiste Malgre Tout, Part II: Les Fruits Verts du Progres", Narrator and interviewer, Jean-Paul Escande [in French, with French and English transcriptions, folder 2]. Channel 2, Paris, France, filmed in 1980 - poor sound quality [U-Matic, transformed from French system; 55 minutes], moving image (Box 110, Tape 12)
  - "L'Optimiste Malgre Tout, Part III: Le Mirage de la Sante", narrator and interviewer, Jean-Paul Escande [in French, with French and English transcriptions, folder 3]. Channel 2, Paris France, filmed in 1980 - poor sound quality [U-Matic, transformed from the French system; 55 minutes], moving image (Box 110, Tape 13)
  - "L'Optimiste Malgre Tout, Part IV: Le Futur Anticipe", narrator and interviewer, Jean-Paul Escande [in French, with French and English transcriptions, folder 4]. Channel 2, Paris, France, filmed in 1980 - poor sound quality [U-Matic, transformed from the French system; 55 minutes], moving image (Box 110, Tape 14)
- (PHOTOGRAPHS)
  - Dubos Family, circa 1900s-1940s (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified man, n.d. [maybe René J. Dubos's father or grandfather] Georges Dubos (René J. Dubos's father) in WWI uniform, [postcard/photograph], 1916
    - Georges Dubos, circa 1908
    - Georges Dubos w/ several men, about to slaughter cow, undated
    - Adeline Dubos (René J. Dubos's mother), circa 1908
    - Adeline Dubos, prewar [WWII]
    - Jeanne Dubos, young adult, 1908
    - Madeleine Dubos, (René J. Dubos's sister), circa 1908
    - Francis Dubos, (René J. Dubos's brother), as child, undated
    - Francis Dubos, young adult, undated
    - Francis Dubos, in uniform [WWII]
    - Francis Dubos, informal, unidentified
    - Group Photograph; René J. Dubos, mother, brother, and sister, 1908
    - Group Photograph, Mother, Jeanne, Marie-Louise [Bonnet], and [?], 1920
    - Group Photograph, René J. Dubos w/ mother, sister, and sister-in-law, circa 1920s
    - Three nuns, unidentified, undated
    - Unidentified man and woman, undated
    - Le Rochambeau, postcard/photograph; ship which René J. Dubos took to U.S. and met Selaman Waksman, undated
  - R. Dubos as Infant and Child, circa 1901-1908 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Group Photograph, 1907 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    RJD as child, Henonville (oise); postcard/photograph.
  - Group Photograph, circa 1920 1930-1933 1947 1958 undated (Box 111, Folder 4)
    RJD informally sitting with unidentified group of people [France?], included in letter from L. Robert Potet [see Correspondence, To and From L. Robert Potet].
  - Informal Portraits, 1921 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    "Gargan Livry".
  - Portrait, 1924? (Box 111, Folder 6)
    First year in U.S.
  - Group Photographs, 1927? (Box 111, Folder 7)
    Rutgers University, N.J., Formal and informal, unidentified individuals.
  - Group Photograph, circa 1928 or 1929 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, International House [informal], included in letter from Armen Khounoutz dated 5/18/84 [see Correspondence, "K"].
  - Portrait, 1928 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    By Louis Schmidt; includes one signed by Dubos.
  - Portraits, circa 1930-1940 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    Formal and informal; Concludes one of RJD in bathrobe, perhaps recuperating in hospital?].
  - Marie-Louise Bonnet [Mrs. René Dubos], circa 1930s-1942 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    Various poses, locations and time periods.
  - Marie-Louise Bonnet [Dubos], circa 1930s-1942 (Box 111, Folder 12)
    Small color snapshots with RJD, "In memory of colors, and of dreams, and of courage".
  - In Laboratory w/ Kenneth Goodner, 1930 or 1932 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    In Avery Lab taken by W.F. Goebel; Dubos "holding mushroom".
  - Group Photograph, 1931 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    The Rockefeller Institute, Scientific and Medical Personnel of The Rockefeller Hospital.
  - Portrait, 1931 May 20 (Box 111, Folder 15)
  - With Andre Draghi at the Tomb of Buffalo Bill, 1934? (Box 111, Folder 16)
    Pictured: Marie-Louise Bonnet and RJD.
  - Portrait, 1938 March 28 (Box 111, Folder 17)
  - Passport Photograph, 1939 (Box 111, Folder 18)
    Department of State.
  - Marie-Louise Bonnet w/ René J. Dubos, circa 1940s (Box 111, Folder 19)
    During visit to upstate NY sanatarium when Marie-Louise had TB.
  - Informal Group Photographs, circa 1940-1948 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Sigma XI Lecture Trip, 1948
    - In Atlantic City with Al Coburn and John Paul, 1940s
  - Informal, circa 1940-1950 (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - Dubos w/ unidentified man, undated
    - Jean Dubos in Lab, undated
    - Dubos in rural area, undated
  - Portraits, circa 1940-1950 (Box 111, Folder 22)
    - Pan-American Photographs
    - Associated Photographic Service, Inc.
    - National Photo Service
    - Lab shots
  - "Meditation", 1940 (Box 111, Folder 23)
    Dubos w/ unidentified man reading newspaper, June.
  - Portraits, 1941 (Box 111, Folder 24)
    Credit: J. Blauvelt-Haulenbeek; one signed by RJD.
  - Informal, 1944-1946 (Box 111, Folder 25)
    - "chez Toby", LRené J. Dubos reclining, in France?], 1944-1946
    - René J. Dubos w/ Emmanuel and Elsa Sutter, Carol Grief [Garrison, NY?], undated
  - Family Group Photograph, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 26)
    RJD, Jean Dubos, Adeleine Dubos, Georges-André, and Jeannette; Paris, France.
  - Informal, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 27)
    Jean and René, Stockholm, Sweden.
    RJD w/ unidentified man, Copenhagen.
  - Portrait, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 28)
    France.
  - Portraits, 1947 (Box 111, Folder 29)
    Jean and René Dubos.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1948 or 1949 (Box 111, Folder 30)
    Virus Symposium, Hertz Mt., "Bird Dinner?", Group photograph w/ Sterns, Mrs. T. Francis, Shopes, Good Pasture, Schuman, Beaudette, Karl Meyer, Hubner, and "English couple." Credit: Boutrel1e-Sevecke Assoc.
  - Informal, 1949 (Box 111, Folder 31)
    Oklahoma or Albuquerque, October 12.
    Taken by Gernez-Rieux.
  - Lab Interiors, 1949 (Box 111, Folder 32)
    Dubos Lab in Smith Hall; Rooms 405, 409, 411, and 412.
  - Jean and René Dubos, "Garrison", 1949 (Box 111, Folder 33)
    Taken by Henriette Noufflard.
  - Informal, circa 1950-1960 (Box 111, Folder 34)
    RJD w/ Dr. Bernard S. Oppenheimer of Mt. Sinai Hospital RJD standing near lake.
  - Portraits, circa 1950-1960 (Box 111, Folder 35)
    - Pan-American Photo Service
    - By Karl Maramrosch [in labcoat]
    - In lab [informal]
    - Small headshots
  - Awards and Honors, 1950 (Box 111, Folder 36)
    Reception, after the Sorbonne Honorary degree.
  - Informal Group Photographs, 1950 (Box 111, Folder 37)
    - w/ Marcia Noyes, Geronimus, Irene Farkas?, Geralee Gallagher, Jane Buckalew, and Flanagan
    - René J. Dubos w/ Rollin D. Hotchkiss
    - René J. Dubos w/ Russell Schaedler, Jim Hirsch, and unidentified nurse René J. Dubos w/ Gernez-Rieux and daughter
  - Informal Laboratory, 1950 (Box 111, Folder 38)
    By Maria Martel.
    RJD at "Farewell Party" before leaving for Europe, November 19.
  - Jean and René Dubos, Garrison, NY, 1950 (Box 111, Folder 39)
    By Maria Martel [includes contact sheets].
  - National Jewish Hospital, 1950 (Box 111, Folder 40)
    Denver, Colorado.
  - Pasteur Institute, 1950 (Box 111, Folder 41)
    RJD during visit, Lille, France.
  - Group Photograph, 1951 (Box 111, Folder 42)
    RIMR, taken by M.W. Chase. Pictured: William Archley, Manny Sutor, Rollin Hotchkiss, Essie Weiss, Jerry Simunck, Marguerite Pentbarge (Strasbury), Cynthia Pierce, (Werner) Bernard Schaefer, James Hirsch, René Dubos, Barbara Craifonte, Geralee Galloway, Irene Farkas, Jean Davidson, Irene S. Slizys, and Jacqueline Moore.
  - René and Jean Dubos, for "White Plague Publicity", by Roger Grief, 1952 (Box 111, Folder 43)
  - Informal, Garrison, NY, circa 1952-1961 (Box 111, Folder 44)
    - Frank Fenner and Dubos digging
    - Dubos' house
    - René J. Dubos and Jean w/ Mary-Ellen (Jennifer) Porter, [Jean's niece], 1961
    - Postcard, Hollins College, Va. [school attended by Mary-Ellen Porter ?, found with above photo]
    - René J. Dubos and Jean w/ "the triplets", children of Francis Dubos [René's brother]
  - Dedication, 1954 (Box 111, Folder 45)
    Institute of Microbiology, Rutgers University. Pictured: Dr. Frank L. Horsfall [Pres. and Director of Sloan Kettering Cancer Research Institute], Dr. Richard Shope, and W.A. Feirer [Director of Squibb].
  - René J. Dubos w/ Cynthia Pierce (Chase), 1954 (Box 111, Folder 46)
    Oxford?.
  - Waksman Institute Opening, 1954-1960? (Box 111, Folder 47)
    RJD pictured w/ Selman Waksman.
  - Awards and Honors, 1955 (Box 111, Folder 48)
    National University, Dublin, Ireland [group photo] Credit: Independent Newspapers, Ltd.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1956 (Box 111, Folder 49)
    First James W. McLaughlin Symposium, Galveston, April 27 [group photo].
  - Centre de L'Enfance, Boulogne, Paris, France, 1957 June? (Box 111, Folder 50)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1958 (Box 111, Folder 51)
    University of Maryland Lecture; RJD w/ Theodore Woodward.
  - Awards and Honors, 1959? (Box 111, Folder 52)
    University of Bologna.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1959 (Box 111, Folder 53)
    - Antibiotic Symposium, November 5, Washington, DC; Credit: Chase Ltd.
    - Centre Internationale L'Enfance, July 27, Boulogne (Paris), France; Credit: Photo Pic. Pictured: René J. Dubos w/ Robert Debre, Dillon, Brazilian Ambassador and Reichman
    - Lectures, University of Brasilia; w/ Irvine Paige
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1959 (Box 111, Folder 54)
    The Rockefeller Institute, Christmas Lectures; Credit: Illustration Service, Rockefeller Institute and one by The New York Times.
  - Portraits, 1959 (Box 111, Folder 55)
    By Rockefeller Institute Illustration Services [one photo signed by RJD].
  - Portraits, circa 1960-1970 (Box 111, Folder 56)
  - Awards and Honors, 1960 (Box 111, Folder 57)
    Dartmouth College, June 12; includes group photo and conferment of honorary degree.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1960 (Box 111, Folder 58)
    Dreams of Reason Conference, The Institute of Physics, Brookhaven, N.Y.
  - Awards and Honors, 1961 (Box 111, Folder 59)
    Albert Einstein Graduation, June; Credit: Ted Burrows.
  - Florida Swamp Trip, 1961 (Box 111, Folder 60)
    [Taken during the December Lectures; RJD not pictured].
  - Group Photographs, 1961 (Box 111, Folder 61)
    L'Institut de Microbiologie et d'Hygiene de L'Université de Montreal, Canada. Pictured: Panniset, David Weiss, D'Arcy Hart, Frappier, Dr. & Mrs. Feldman, Dr. & Mrs. Vandiviere, and F.M. Levy.
    National Institutes of Health Public service, U.S. Department of Health, Education, & Welfare, Bethesda, Maryland.
  - Informal, circa 1961 (Box 111, Folder 62)
    - René J. Dubos in labcoat
    - On RI campus[?], in tree
    - w/ unidentified Soviet holding Russian edition of Bacterial Cell
    - w/ unidentified man from the Research Institute for Mother and Child Welfare in Warsaw and [?]
  - Informal Laboratory, 1961 (Box 111, Folder 63)
    Holding petri dishes, test tube, mouse, looking through microscope. Also w/ Russell Schaedler "discussing the results of an experiment." Credit: Illustration Service, Rockefeller Institute.
  - Portrait, 1961 (Box 111, Folder 64)
    One signed by RJD.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1962 (Box 111, Folder 65)
    - Herzstein Medical Lectures, San Francisco, Ca. March Pictured: Esysy and Provost Saunders
    - Holiday Lectures, Cincinnati, OH; Credit: Howard A. Newman
    - The National Institutes of Health, History of Medicine Study Section, Besthesda, Md., January 19
      Includes: Dr. Owsei Tmkin, Dr. Saul Jarcho, and Dr. David Shakow.
    - Pan American Conference, Washington, DC, June; w/ Walsh McDermott
    - Unidentified Conference. René J. Dubos w/ Armand Frappier and Maurice Panisset, Montreal, Canada, November 6
  - Lab Interiors, 1962 1964 (Box 111, Folder 66)
    Dubos Lab - South lab, 4th floor, Rooms 415 and 402.
  - Portrait, 1962 (Box 111, Folder 67)
    "From Go Berry, Bryn Mawr" [informal].
  - "Soiree Musicale", 1962 (Box 111, Folder 68)
    Dinner party; includes: Dr. Eugene Bernstein, Von Euler, Saunders, Costello, and Yarney.
  - Awards and Honors, 1963 (Box 111, Folder 69)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Award in Science w/ Richard Hofstadter and Joan Webber
    - Edmonton, Alberta, Canada, Doctor of Laws, September
    - Key to the City of San Juan
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1963 (Box 111, Folder 70)
    Waldeman Medical Research Foundation, High School Scientists, Port Washington, N.Y. credit: Newsday.
  - Dinner Given by Dr. Eugene Bernstein in Honor of 30th Anniversary in U.S., 1963 October 19 (Box 111, Folder 71)
  - Portrait, circa 1963 (Box 111, Folder 72)
  - Awards and Honors, 1964 (Box 112, Folder 1)
    American Medical Association Scientific Achievement Award, June. Credit: Moulin Studios. Pictured: Dr. Percy E. Hopkins [Chairman of AMA Board of Trustees].
  - Convocation, 1964 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    The Rockefeller Institute, June 12.
  - Group Photographs, 1964 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    American College of Physicians, Regional Meeting, January 14 Trudeau Foundation, Saranac Lake, August 1.
  - Jack Daniels Distillery, Tennessee, 1964 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    w/ Dave and Corky Rogers, Vanderbilt, and RJD and Jean Dubos.
  - Awards and Honors, 1965 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    Institute of Medicine, Society of Internal Medicine, Chicago, Ill., February 22. Pictured: Holinger, Strohl, and McEwen? Credit: Richard Klein.
    University of Pennsylvania, Founder's Day Convocation, January 23. Pictured: Dr. Gaylord Harwell, Dr. George Berry, Dr. John Gibbon, Jr., Senator Lister Hill, Dr. Seymour Kety, Dr. Carl Schmidt, Dr. Ravdin, and Dr. David Goddard; Credit: Jules Schick.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1965 (Box 112, Folder 6)
    Cutler-Hamer Symposium, "New Worlds in the Making", Milwaukee, WI.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1965 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    INCAP, Guatemala, [NIH], Pan American Health Organization [see also slides].
  - Group Photograph, 1965 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Jean and René Dubos w/ CP. and Florence Miller. Credit: Richard Klein
  - Informal Portrait, 1965 (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - René J. Dubos and Russell Schaedler, sent by Life magazine (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Awards and Honors, 1966 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    Arches of Science Award [from scrapbook; see also, Scrapbook, Arches of Science Award, 1966].
  - Awards and Honors, 1966 (Box 112, Folder 11)
    Colby College, Waterville, Maine, June.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1966 (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Cornell Medical School - NY Hospital, Public Health Class, April
    - Jean Dubos, The College of Wooster, "The Pursuit of Significance", February 14-19
    - Rutgers University, "The Environment, The University, and the Welfare of Man", October 17. Credit: Rutgers University
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture
    - Unidentified lecture - contact sheets
  - NASA Manned Spacecraft Center Visit, 1966 (Box 112, Folder 13)
    Houston, Texas, June 27.
  - Ohio Agricultural Research Station Visit, 1966 (Box 112, Folder 14)
    "germ-free piglets".
  - Awards and Honors, Wesleyan University, June 3, 1967 (Box 112, Folder 15)
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1967 (Box 112, Folder 16)
    Conference on Comparative Medicine, National Institute of General Medical Sciences (NIH) - Workshop, Bethesda Md. Pictured: Prof. E.C. Amoroso and Dr. Stone. Credit: Tom Joy. Also group photo of workshop participants.
    RJD delivering unidentified lecture.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1967 (Box 112, Folder 17)
    International Conference on Gynecology and Obstetrics, Sidney, Australia; Also includes informal dinner photos.
  - Convocation, 1967 (Box 112, Folder 18)
    The Rockefeller University [informal], w/ Richard Krause and Neil Miller.
  - Awards and Honors, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 19)
    Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario, November 6-9.
    St. John's University, New York, June 9.
  - Awards and Honors, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 20)
    Two Cultures Award, Flushing High School, New York, March 26 ["35mm negatives in negative file"].
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 21)
    - Briarcliff College Lecture and Reception, "Biologic Remembrance", April 11
    - Department of State Science Lectures, December 9; Credit
    - Department of State Photo
    - National Institute of Mental Health,. Pictured: Dr. Bertram Brown, May 30
    - School Health Education Study Think Conference, Airlie House, Warrenton, VA, "Human Potential in a Dynamic Environment", [group], June 9-11
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 22)
    Pfizer 16th Annual Research Conference, Washington, D.C. Pictured: Dr. A.H. Jensen, Dr. S.L. Hansard, Dr. R.H. Thayer, Dr. R. Yamamoto, R.M. Hendrickson, J.J. Thompson, and W.P. Crawford. Credit: City News Bureau, Inc.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 23)
    Taiwan, Lecture Tour, Taiwan University-Medical School, September 17-24.
  - Dedication of Chamberlin Science Center, 1968 (Box 112, Folder 24)
    Belait College, Wisconsin.
  - Awards and Honors, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 25)
    L'Université de Sherbrook, Canada.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 26)
    Parisot Lecture, "Human Ecology", World Health Assembly, Boston, MA.
  - Group Photographs, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 27)
    University of Cincinnati, Medical Center. Pictured: J. Barzun, M. DeBakey, Bishop Blanchard, Justice Bazelon and C. [Aring ?].
    Unidentified, [Europe?].
  - Informal Portrait, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 28)
    Credit: Today's Health.
  - Interview, 1969 (Box 112, Folder 29)
    German T.V. Credit: Atelier Films.
  - Laboratory, 1969-1968? (Box 112, Folder 30)
    RJD w/ mouse on scale.
  - Rencontres De Monaco [Meeting in Monaco], 1969 (Box 112, Folder 31)
    Les Premiers Jours de la Vie.
    Includes photo of Princess Grace.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1970 (Box 112, Folder 32)
    Parks Council Annual Meeting, w/ Richard Eades Harrison.
  - Portraits, 1970 (Box 112, Folder 33)
    Monastery Regina Laudis, Behtlehem, CT. Credit: Henrik Boudakian, used for Only One Earth, includes photo of Barbara Ward, co-author.
  - Schlitz Brewery, 1970-1971 (Box 112, Folder 34)
    Milwaukee and Salem NC; w/ Robert A. Viklein, Ben Barkin and others.
  - Awards and Honors, 1971 (Box 112, Folder 35)
    - Bard College, honorary degree of Doctor of Science and commencement speaker, May 29. Credit: Zach Bregman
    - International House. Credit: Candido Photography Marquette University, Milwaukee, Wise.- address
    - René J. Dubos w/ Glen and Lorie Paulson, June 3 [unidentified campus]
  - Portrait, 1971 (Box 112, Folder 36)
    Modern Maturity Magazine.
  - 70th Birthday Celebration, 1971 (Box 112, Folder 37)
    Pictured: Deltev Bronk, Walsh McDermott, Glen Paulson, Carol Moberg, Clara Lynch, Cynthia Pierce, Zanvil Cohn, Robert Fauve, Steve Morse, James Hirsch, and Rollin D. Hotchkiss.
  - René J. Dubos w/ Telephone Operator, 1971 (Box 112, Folder 38)
    Cleveland Art Museum, OH [December 1, 1970 speech at Museum].
  - Awards and Honors, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 39)
    University of Calgary, Convocation.
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 40)
    - Conference on the Environment, Stockholm, Sweden. Pictured: Olaf Palme, P.M. of Sweden
    - Delos Symposium (Doxiadis). Pictured: Mr. & Mrs. Robert O. Anderson and Santorini
    - Manhattan College, Pacem in Terris Institute, October 15. Pictured: Hans Morgenthau, Vietnam Buddist, Danilo Dolci, and Tom Stanier
  - The God Within, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 41)
    RJD w/ clipping shears, Garrison, N.Y. Credit: Lawrence Moberg.
  - "The Greening of Bloomingda1e's, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 42)
    Park Council.
  - Informal Portraits, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 43)
    Department of Agriculture [in labcoat], Columbus, Indiana.
  - Interview, T.V., 1972 April 13 (Box 112, Folder 44)
    Hugh Downs Show, informal shots.
  - Natural Resources Defense Council Dinner, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 45)
    Given by Beneck.
  - Portrait, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 46)
    Contact sheets; Credit: Jill Kementz, Meridan Photographics.
  - Portrait, 1972 or 1973 (Box 112, Folder 47)
    The Rockefeller University.
  - The Trudeau Institute, 1972 (Box 112, Folder 48)
    Rabbit Island.
  - Awards and Honors, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 50)
    Emmy Award (T.V.), "Spaceship Earth".
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 51)
    - American Lung Association, May. Credit: Cosmo Photographs
    - Prospective et Sante Publique, May [debates]
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, St. Regis-Maisonette, April
    - The Worldwide Management Conference, Boca Raton, FLA, May 21-24. Pictured: Marc Lauvergeon, Claude Etchegary and Henri Busignier
    - City Planning Conference, Vail Colorado, August. Pictured: John Lindsay
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 52)
    "Hommage à Louis Pasteur", L'Institut De France, May 7. Credit: J. Mainbourg [see also, Conferences and Lectures, 1973].
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 53)
    unidentified, "At the Biltmore, 12/5/73".
  - Group Photograph, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 54)
    Nichiren Shoshi Academy, Santa Monica CA. Pictured: Joanne Murad, George M. Williams, Harvey Hall, and Roy Nishida and Jean Dubos.
  - Informal Portraits, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 55)
    On the RU campus; Credit: Ingbet [various poses].
  - Informal Shots, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 56)
    Aspen, Colorado, August [Human Needs and Natural Limits - Aspen Institute for humanistic Studies?].
  - Portraits, 1973? (Box 112, Folder 57)
    In labcoat [informal].
  - Trip to Japan - Scrapbook, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 58)
    - Loose photographs found in scrapbook binder
    - René J. Dubos w/ cat
    - passport photo of Jean and René, 1947
    - Greeting unidentified man, 1973
      [See also, Scrapbook, Trip to Japan, 1973].
  - Trip to Japan - Scrapbook, 1973 (Box 112, Folder 59)
    Reception, lecture, TV news show, sightseeing, farwell dinner.
  - Awards and Honors, 1974 (Box 112, Folder 60)
    - Jefferson Medical School Honorary, June 7. Pictured: Russell Schaedler. Credit: Peter A. Kind III
    - Forsythia Award, April 18. Pictured: Mrs. F. Tuttle and John R.H. Blum. Credit: Brooklyn Botanical Garden
  - Conferences and Lectures, 1974 (Box 112, Folder 61)
    Alumni Program for Health Professionals, St. John's University, April 24. Credit: George Jervas.
  - Greece, (Cos), 1974 (Box 112, Folder 62)
    Reception upon arrival.
  - Group Photograph, 1974 (Box 112, Folder 63)
    Mexico, "After the horse show at fiesta" [American Institute of Architects], October.
  - Hotel de Ville, "Signing and Gala", Paris, France [city hall ?], 1974 July 4 (Box 112, Folder 64)
    [UNESCO House 1st World Congress of Environmental Medicine and Biology, Paris, July 1-5]. Pictured: Abbou, Mme Saeny, Pierre Pellerin, and others. Credit: Actualites Mondial Photo.
  - Informal, 1974 August 27 (Box 112, Folder 65)
    Jean and René, "Going away party for Dick Costello".
  - Informal, 1974 March 11 (Box 112, Folder 66)
    RJD w/ Barabara Ward; The Rockefeller University Council.
  - Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    Pictured: Mayor Abraham Beame. Credit: Dick De Marisco.
  - Informal Group Photographs, 1975 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    Arc et Lenans, October.
  - Informal Portraits, 1975 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    Credit: Rhoda Nathans.
    Credit: Mia Smith; several poses.
  - Awards and Honors, 1976 (Box 113, Folder 4)